Table of Contents

1. Introduction

Alejandro Tapia Bueno

Mobile: (55) 6243 5831

Email: alejandro_tapia@outlook.com

Click using Cmd + Left Click if you're on a Mac or Ctrl + Left Click if you're using Windows

Introduction

I'm 27 years old and i'm a web developer.

I am a person with initiative and motivation, and I love learning and trying new stuff, whether it's Atole agrio or Firebase.

While working on a project I act by the words my dad once said to me "Don't do something a computer could", meaning not to waste ourselves working in repetitive or boring tasks but instead to create pieces of software to help us and to make our lives easier. Because of that a colleague once said to me "You solve problems no one had seen".

Experience

Paradigma Cero (2011 - 2015)

From 2011 to 2015 I worked full time as Lead Developer for Paradigma Cero, a Digital Marketing Agency.

At this agency my responsabilities included:

- to Develop web projects for our customers.
- to Maintain and update regularly several websites.
- to Create HTML documents intended to be sent via Email (Emailings & Newsletters).
- to Review other developers's work.
- to Optimize web sites for SEO.

Aditionally to the activities described in my job description I:

- Refocused several projects, from an email-based workflow to a project-based one, using Open Atrium to centralize information and resources.
- Before my arrival no CMS was being take advantage of. my first project in the agency was a migration from a file-based blog to Joomla.
- I developed a series of web apps which allowed our customers to create html documents for emailing without need of prior programming knowledge (WYSIWYG like).
- Implemented VCS company-wide using Git and Bitbucket.
- Wrote a spec on form development standardization
- Forced several jr developers on using Sublime text the right way

Convergencia Estado de México (2007 - 2009)

From 2005 to 2007 I worked part time and on project-basis for Political Party "Convergencia" (now "Movimiento Ciudadano") Chapter "Estado de México".

As external contractor my responsabilities included:

• to Maintain and update regularly Convergencia Estado de México's website.

Education

Med School (unfinished) at Universidad Autónoma del Estado de México (2005 - 2011).

Courses and Additional Education

- Hubspot Inbound Marketing Training
- MOZ Academy Training
- User Experience for the Web
- Shaping up with Angular.js
- Getting Started with Ruby on Rails
- McCullough and Berglund on Mastering Git

Projects

Riviera (2014)

rivieramx.com.mx

Simplot México (2013)

simplotmexico.com

Balper México (2013)

balper.com.mx

Web Technologies Expertise

HTML

- HTML5 Specification
 - new HTML elements
 - new Browser API's and Technologies
 - localStorage
 - IndexDB
 - History API

Frameworks, libraries and classes I use

• HTML5 Boilerplate

CSS

- Box Model
- CSS version 3
 - Media Queries
 - CSS Flexible Box Layout module
 - CSS Backgrounds & Borders
- SASS

Frameworks, libraries and classes I use

- Bourbon
- Bootstrap
- Foundation
- MetroUI

Javascript

- Ajax requests and API consumption in conjunction with WebServices
- localStorage
- IndexDB
- History API

Frameworks, libraries and classes I use

- jQuery
- MomentJS
- AngularJS
- AccountingJS
- Iscache
- taffydb
- crossroads JS

PHP

- PDO
- OOP
- MVC
- Composer
- · WebServices, API

Frameworks, libraries and classes I use

- Bento
- Twig
- PHP-MySQL-PDO-Database-Class
- PHPMailer

SEO

- Site wide optimization (PageSpeed Score)
- On page optimization
- Conversion optimization

Languages

- Spanish: native
- English: speak/read/write with high proficiency

Technical Skills

- Basic administration of *NIX based systems to act as web servers.
- Mac OS, Windows and Ubuntu (for web development I prefer Mac OS).
- Office I Google Docs